simpson.edu 2019-05-01

# Privacy Policy | Simpson College

#### Introduction

Simpson College (“The College” or “we/our/us”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”). This Privacy Policy refers to the gathering, storing, processing, use, and disclosure practices for the domains (the “Sites”) owned by The College, including: simpson.edu; choose.simpson.edu; recruit.simpson.edu, and simpsonathletics.com.

By accessing or using the Sites, you are consenting to the application of this Privacy Policy to your Personal Information.  This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of the Sites after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for updates.

Please note that this Privacy Policy applies only to your Personal Information that Simpson College collects from you through the Sites. It does not apply to information that The College or The College’s affiliates may collect from you through any other means, or to information collected by third parties that may link to or be accessible from the Sites.

#### Information Collected by The College

  * While you use the Sites, The College may collect information from you or about you using various methods, including: 
    * Personal Information that you willingly provide by filling out forms within the Sites. Some of the forms include, but are not limited to, online applications for admission, information requests, contests and event registrations;
    * Records and copies of your correspondence through the Sites with us; and
    * Information about your use of the Sites, which is collected automatically as you navigate through the Sites.
  * Using the methods described above, we collect several types of information from or about you: 
    * Information by which you may be personally identified, such as your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, employer name, graduation year, high school, and any other information by which you may be contacted online or offline (“Personal Information”);
    * Information that relates to you or your activities but that does not identify you as an individual; and
    * Information about the equipment you use to access our Sites.

#### Information Collected Automatically

As you navigate through and interact with the Sites, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information, including (i) details of your use, including traffic data, logs and other communication data and the resources that you access and use and (ii) information about your computer, including your operating system, IP address, and other data.

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include cookies. A cookie is a small and common file placed on your device. At any point you may refuse to accept cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your device. However, if you select this setting, you may be unable to use certain features of our Sites.

Third parties’ use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this Privacy Policy. Third parties do not have access to our cookies.

#### How We Use Your Information

We use information that we collect about you, including any Personal Information, for the following purposes:

  * To provide, enhance, improve and develop our Sites and our services, including measuring and improving the Sites’ content and layout;
  * To provide you with information or services that you request from us;
  * To resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems;
  * To prevent potentially unsafe, prohibited, or illegal activities and enforce this Privacy Policy and any applicable licensing agreements between The College and relevant third parties and any terms and conditions associated therewith;
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts related to the Sites and entered into between you and us;
  * To notify you about changes to our Sites or any services that we offer;
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide such information;
  * To support maintenance operations for the Sites or for the purpose of diagnosing/resolving any problems that might limit/disrupt the quality of users’ experience;
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information; and
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

#### Use of Your Information to Communicate with You

We may use your Personal Information to respond to communications from you.  This may include e-mail, text messages, and other forms of communication.  In certain cases, you may be able to opt out of receiving such communications via using the opt-out mechanism within certain emails, or by contacting us via phone, email or postal mail. Contact information is provided at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

#### How Information is Shared

We respect your privacy and will never sell your Personal Information to an outside source.  However, there are certain instances where we may professionally disclose information, including Personal Information, that we collect from or about you on the Sites:

  * **To our affiliates** ;
  * **To Service Providers** , such as contractors, consultants and other agents that provide assistance to our business and the operation and maintenance of the Sites. 
    * Service Providers with whom we share such information, unless we tell you differently, do not have any right to use the information we share with them beyond the scope and duration of what is necessary to assist us;
  * **For any other purpose disclosed by us**  when you provide the information;
  * **For any purpose with your consent**. 
    * For example, we may share your information with third parties to whom you explicitly ask us to send your information.; and
  * **As required by law**. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this Privacy Policy, we also reserve the right to access, preserve, use and disclose any information as we reasonably believe is necessary, in our sole discretion: 
    * (i) to respond to legal requirements, including complying with any court order, law or legal process and responding to any government or regulatory request, including responding to law enforcement or other government officials in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity;
    * (ii) to enforce or apply our policies and agreements;
    * (iii) to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security, trust and safety or technical issues; or
    * (iv) to protect the rights, property, health or safety of The College, our users, any third parties or the public in general.

We may also create aggregate information about our users and their use of the Sites, which information does not identify any particular user. We use this aggregated information to monitor and improve our products and services. We also may disclose this anonymized, aggregated information to people and entities with whom we do business and to market our products and services.

#### Credit Card Information

When necessary for payments related to your use of the Sites, your credit card information will be collected and processed outside of the Sites, by a third-party payment processor. This Privacy Policy does not govern the practices of third-party payment processors, and, if you disclose your information to a third-party payment processor, different rules may apply to its use and disclosure of the information you disclose to such third-party payment processor. You acknowledge that if you provide information to third-party payment processors, that information will be subject to their user agreements, terms and conditions of sale, privacy policies and other applicable policies and agreements, which may differ from this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the policies of third-party payment processors.

#### Third Party Services

The College’s Sites may contain third party services, applications or links to outside sources (“Third-Party Services”).  If you elect to access and use Third-Party Services through the Sites, you acknowledge that this Privacy Policy addresses only The College’s collection, use and disclosure of information collected by The College from you through the Sites. It does not apply to the practices of Third-Parties Services that we do not own, control, employ or manage. If you disclose your information to a Third-Party Service, including through the Sites, the information disclosed will be subject to the privacy policies and user agreements associated with those Third-Party Services. We are not responsible for the content, user agreements or privacy policies of Third-Party Services.

These Third-Party Services may also use cookies or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use our Site. The information they collect may be associated with your personal information. We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used.

#### Children

Our Sites are not intended for children under 13 years of age, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. No one under the age of 13 may provide any information to the Site, including, for example, a name, telephone number or email address. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information.

#### Security

Unfortunately, information transmitted through the internet or other communication networks may not be completely secure, and third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Although we work hard to protect your privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of information or that your Personal Information or private communications always will remain private. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time. Any transmission of Personal Information is at your own risk, and we are not responsible for the circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained within the Sites.

#### Changes to the Privacy Policy

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended Privacy Policy on this page. The date the Privacy Policy was last revised is identified at the top of this Privacy Policy. All amended terms automatically take effect after they are initially posted on this page, unless a change in any applicable law requires immediate amendment. You are responsible for periodically checking this Privacy Policy for any changes.

#### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Sites that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us using one of the methods below

#### Questions & Concerns

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact Simpson College’s Office of Marketing and Public Relations at:

**Phone:**  515-961-1606  
 **Email:  **success@simpson.edu  
 **Postal Address:**  Simpson College, Office of Marketing and Public Relations, 701 North C Street, Indianola, IA 50125
